{
  "angular": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Which of the following is correct?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Angular is based on TypeScript.",
        "B": "This is a superset of JavaScript.",
        "C": "TypeScript is maintained by Microsoft.",
        "D": "All of the above."
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "What is .subscribe?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Streams data in asynchronously",
        "B": "Streams data in synchronously",
        "C": "Both",
        "D": "None of the Above"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "What does AOT stand for?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Ahead-Of-Time Compilation",
        "B": "Angular Object Templates",
        "C": "Both",
        "D": "None of the Above"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Which of the following is not a hook application life cycle?",
      "options": {
        "A": "ngOnChanges",
        "B": "ngViewStart",
        "C": "ngOnInit",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Router is part of which of the following module?",
      "options": {
        "A": "@angular/core",
        "B": "@angular/router",
        "C": "Both",
        "D": "None of the above"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    }
  ],
  "springboot": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Spring Boot is used for developing?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Web applications",
        "B": "Distributed applications (Restful web services)",
        "C": "Microservices.",
        "D": "All of the above."
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "What is Spring Initializer?",
      "options": {
        "A": "A web-based tool for generating a basic Spring Boot project structure",
        "B": "A command-line tool for generating a basic Spring Boot project structure",
        "C": "A tool for initializing a Spring-based application with a specific set of dependencies",
        "D": "A tool for creating a Spring Boot application with a specific set of features"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "What does Spring Boot do to simplify the configuration of a Spring-based application?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Automatically configures necessary beans and dependencies",
        "B": "Uses annotations to configure beans and dependencies",
        "C": "Allows for the use of XML configuration files",
        "D": "Provides a command line interface for configuring the application"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "How can a Spring Boot application be packaged and distributed?",
      "options": {
        "A": "As a JAR file ",
        "B": "As a WAR file ",
        "C": "As a ZIP file",
        "D": "All of the above"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": " Which Spring annotation is used to create RESTful web services using Spring MVC?",
      "options": {
        "A": "@RestController",
        "B": "@Controller",
        "C": "@Component",
        "D": "@Rest"
      },
      "answer": "A"
    }
  ],
  "javascript": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Javascript is an _______ language?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Object Oriented",
        "B": "Object-based",
        "C": "Procedural",
        "D": "None of the above."
      },
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Which of the following keywords is used to define a variable in Javascript?",
      "options": {
        "A": "var",
        "B": "let",
        "C": "Both A &B",
        "D": "None of the Above"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Which of the following methods is used to access HTML elements using Javascript?",
      "options": {
        "A": "getElementById()",
        "B": "getElementByClassName()",
        "C": "Both A& B",
        "D": "None of the Above"
      },
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Upon encountering empty statements, what does the Javascript Interpreter do?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Throws an Error ",
        "B": "Ignores the statements ",
        "C": "Gives a warning",
        "D": "None of the Above"
      },
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Which of the following methods can be used to display data in some form using Javascript?",
      "options": {
        "A": "document.write()",
        "B": "console.log()",
        "C": "window.alert()",
        "D": "All of the above"
      },
      "answer": "D"
    }
  ]
}
